<bibdata type="standard" schema-version="v1.2.9">
  <fetched>2026-02-16</fetched>
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">OGC® Geospatial User Feedback Standard: Conceptual Model</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">OGC® Geospatial User Feedback Standard: Conceptual Model</title>
  <uri type="src">http://www.opengis.net/doc/IS/guf-conceptual/1.0.0</uri>
  <uri type="html">https://docs.ogc.org/is/15-097r1/15-097r1.html</uri>
  <docidentifier type="OGC" primary="true">15-097r1</docidentifier>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2016-12-22</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="author"/>
    <person>
      <name>
        <completename>Joan Masó</completename>
      </name>
    </person>
  </contributor>
  <contributor>
    <role type="author"/>
    <person>
      <name>
        <completename>Lucy Bastin </completename>
      </name>
    </person>
  </contributor>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Open Geospatial Consortium</name>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <edition>1</edition>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">This standard defines a conceptual Geospatial User Feedback (GUF) data model. Geospatial User Feedback is metadata that is predominantly produced by the consumers of geospatial data products as they use and gain experience with those products. This standard complements existing metadata conventions whereby documents recording dataset characteristics and production workflows are generated by the creator, publisher or curator of a data product. As a part of metadata, the GUF data model reuses some elements of ISO 19115-1:2014 (the updated version of the OGC Abstract Specification Topic 11) but not the general structure. This selective use of ISO metadata elements prioritizes future interoperability with developing ISO metadata models. This standard is designed to be used combination with an encoding standard. Initially an XML encoding following the ISO 19139 encoding rules is specified in a separate OGC implementation standard (OGC 15-098). In the future other encodings may be defined, including examples such as the use of JSON-LD based on parts of schema.org.</abstract>
  <ext schema-version="v1.0.1">
    <doctype>standard</doctype>
    <subdoctype>implementation</subdoctype>
    <editorialgroup>
      <committee>technical</committee>
    </editorialgroup>
  </ext>
</bibdata>